Guide to the Child Study Center, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of Donald J. Cohen as director, 1976-2001; Accession 2008-A-099
  - WAR and URBAN TRAUMA: CHILDREN'S DEVELOPMENT AND THEIR PSYCOLOGICAL ADAPTIONS TO CATASTROPHIC EXPERIENCES, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - GROUNDBREAKING: SLIFKA CENTER FOR JEWISH LIFE AT YALE, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - CONTEMPORARY TREATMENT MODELS FOR CHILDREN AND ADOLESCENTS, AACAP, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - URBAN TRAUMA: PHENOMENOLOGY and TREATMENT OF CHILDDREN EXPOSED TO TRAUMA IN THE INNER CITY AND DURING WAR, AACAP, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - AACAP, SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - JOHN DESTEFANO PRESS CONFERENCE, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - D.X. FREEDMAN. M.D. MEMORIAL STATEMENT, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - TOURETTE'S SYNDROME BIOILOGICAL and PSYCHODYNAMIC MODELS OF DEVELOPMENTAL PSYCHOPATHOLOGY, MCLEAN HOSPITAL, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - EVALUATION OF CONTEMPORARY TREATMENT IN MODELS: CONCEPTS AND ISSUES IN THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM FOR CHILDREN AND ADOLESCENTS, LATIN AMERICAN, CHILE, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - 5 computer files (DOC)
  - NEW ENGLAND COUNCIL OF CHILD AND ADLOESCENT PSYCHIATRY, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - WAR AND URBAN TRAUMA: CHILDREN DEVELOPMENT and THEIR PSYCHOLOGIVAL ADAPTIONS TO CATASTROPHIC EXPERIENCES WOODRO WILSON CENTER, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - THE SOCIAL MATRIX OF LOVE ANAGGRESSION: ENACTMENTS, REPRESENTATIONS AND SELF UNDERSTANDING IN THE FIRST YEARS OF LIFE, JERUSALEM, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - KARMASON LECTURE, THE NEW YORK HOSPITAL-CORNELL MEDICAL CENTER, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - THE PSYCHOANALYTIC CHILD: EXERIENCES AND THE INNER WORLD, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - APPLYING DEVELOPMENTAL CONCEPTS AND METHODS TO THE STUDY OF CHILD and ADOLESCENT PSYCHOPATH. NIMH, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - PSYCHOSOCIAL THERAPIES FOR CHILDREN AND ADOLESCENTS: OVERVIEW AND FUTURE DIRECTIONS, NIMH, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - PLAY IN PSYCHOANALYSIS and DEVELOPMENT, CSC CONCERENCE, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - PLAYING IN PSYCHOANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT: THEORETICAL AND CLINICAL ISSUES, TEL AVIV UNIVERSITY, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - PLAY IN PSYCHOANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT, ANNA FREUD CENTRE, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - INTREGRATING BIOLOGICAL AND BEHAVIORAL PERSPECTIVES IN THE STUDY AND CARE OF AUTISTIC INDIVIDUALS: THE FUTURE AHEAD, THE HAGUE, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - DANIEL X. FREEDMAN SYMPOSIUM APA MEETING: WASHINGTON, DC, DANIEL X. FREEDMAN: EMBODIED MIND IN ACTION, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - PLAYING AND PSYCHOANALYSIS: AMERIVAN PSYCHOANALYTIC ASSOC. PANEL ON ANALYSIS OF THE "UNANALYZABLE PATIENT," JUDITH CHAUSED, CHAIR, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - CHILD HEALTH: ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF PROGRESS AND TODAY'S CHALLENGES, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Annual reports
    - 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 147 - 148)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 149 - 150)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 153 - 154)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 157 - 158)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - 1976 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - 1975 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - RESEARCH IN DEVELOPMENTAL PSYCHOPATHOLOGY AND CHILD PSYCHOANALYSIS ROME, ITALY, 1996 April 29 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - ASCAPAP, TOKYO, JAPAN, 1996 April 18-19 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - DEVELOPMENTAL PSYCHOPATHOLOGY IN PRESCHOOL AGE: NEW PATHOGENTTIC MODELS ROME, ITALY, 1996 April 30 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - VIOLENCE: NATIONAL AND INTERNATIONAL. CHILD PSYCHOANALYSIS and CHILD PSYCHIATRY AT THE FRONT PRAGER LECTURE, 1996 May (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - PHILOSOPHY, PSYCHOLOGY AND THE CARE OF CHILDREN PHI BETA KAPPA LECTURE BRANDEIS UNIVERSITY, 1996 May (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - BRAIN DEVELOPMENT IN YOUNG CHILDREN: NEW FRONTIERS FOR RESEARCH FAMILIES AND WORK INSTITUTE, CHICAGO, 1996 June 13-14 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - CHILD STUDY CONFERENCE, 1996 September 10 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - TRANSCRIPT FOR ELLY ZAINUL SESSION #1, 1985 May 10 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - TRANSCRIPT FOR BRIAN C. SESSION #1, undated (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - TRANSCRIPT FOR BRIAN C. SESSION #2, undated (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - TRANSCRIPT FOR BRIAN C. SESSION #3, undated (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - DRAFT, 1986 February 12 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - OEDIPAL MIND, NO DATE (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - CHILD ANALYSIS PLAY GROVE, undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - PLAY STOUG, undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - CHILD PSYCHIATRY COURSE, undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - EXPERIMENTS TO DO, undated (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - SALIVARY STUDY, undated (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - SALIVA STUDY, undated (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - SPEECHES, LECTURES, NOTES, undated (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - DEVELOPMENTAL DIAGNOSIS SUPPLEMENTAL SECURITY INCOME (SSI) NCOCY. DHEW. WASHINGTON, D.C., 1976 November 20 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - CHILDHOOD AUTISM AND ATYPICAL DEVELOPMENTAL, undated (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - SPEECH FOR WNEIP, 1982 June (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - HADASSAH SPEECH, 1982 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - CHINA SPEECH AT APA, 1983 May (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - SOLNIT RECEPTION, 1983 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - BRANDEIS SPEECH AND GRADUATION, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - ALEWITH SPEECHES AACP, 1983 October (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - "TICS AND STERYOTYPIES" THE HOSPITAL OF ST. RAPHEL, 1983 October 3 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - CHAIRMAN'S CASE CONFERENCE BROWN UNIVERSITY, 1984 March 1 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - WNEIP AND CASE, 1984 March 3 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - SOCIETY OF PROFESSORS OF CHILD PSYCHIATRY TUSCON, ARIZONA, 1984 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - UNIVERSITY OF UTAH, 1984 March 21 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - BOSTON PSYCHOANALYTIC SOCIETY, 1984 April 7 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - MOE B. ROSENTHAL LECTURER, 1984 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - SPPECH/APA, undated (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - DEVELOPMENTAL LUNCH PRESENTATION, 1984 December 5 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - PDD LECTURE, undated (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - AACP, 1984 October 14 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - ADD LECTURE, undated (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - CLINICAL RESEARCH IN THE CLINIC - WEST HAVEN CLINIC, 1985 February 1 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - B'NAI JACOB SPEECH, 1985 March 10 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - VISITING LECTURER: UC AT SAN FRANCISCO, 1985 March 21-22 (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - COMMUNICATION DISORDERS DEPT. SOUTHERN CONNECTICUT STATE UNIVERSITY, 1985 April 25 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - JEWISH THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY, 1985 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - DREYFUS MEMORIAL LECTURE, 1985 June 6-7 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - CLIFFORD BEERS LECTURE, 1985 October 14 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - KOREAN SPEECH, 1985 October 17 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - OPENING CEREMONY: CHILDREN'S PSYCHIATRIC INPATIENT SERVICE, 1985 November 22 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - NIMH, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - ASSOCIATES, 1985 November 22 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - CONFERENCE ON DEVELOPMENTAL APPROACHES TO THE ASSESSMENT OF PSYCHOPATHOLOGY NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF MENTAL HEALTH WASHINGTON, D.C., 1992 November (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - BOAZ LECTURE: NEUROBIOLOGY and THE INNER LIVES OF CHILDREN, 1991 January 13 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - ASSOCIATION FOR CHILD PSYCHOANALYSIS ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI, 1991 March 22-24 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - SRCD SEATTLE, WASHINGTON, 1991 April 17-20 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - WNEIP SYMPOSIUM, 1991 April 28 (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - INTRODUCTION OF SENATOR JAY ROCKEFELLER FOR THE CLIFFORD BEERS LECTURE, 1991 May 6 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - AGRESSION IN THE PLAYROOM BOSTON UNIVERSITY JACK SCHWARTZ LECTURE, 1991 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - TOURETTE'S SYNDROME: BIOLOGICAL AND PSYCHOLOGICAL PERSPECTIVES ON A DEVELOPMENTAL AND MULTIGENERATIONAL DISORDER INTERNATIONAL TS SYMPOSIUM, BOSTON, 1991 June 16-18 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - THE PSYCHOANALYTIC CONCEPT OF CONSTITUTION: THE FIRST STAGE OF PSYCHOSEXUAL DEVELOPMENT, 1991 July 7 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - CHILD AND ADOLESCENT MENTAL HEALTH: NEUROBIOLOGICAL and SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE AND THEIR APPLICATION FOR CHILDREN FAM., 1991 September 27 (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - CHILD and ADOLESCENT MENTAL HEALTH MENTAL HEALTH WEEK SYMPOSIUM HARTFORD, 1991 October 10 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - AACAP: SAN FRANCISCO, NATIONAL COMM. ON CHILDREN: BEYOND RHETORIC, 1991 October 16-20 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - ANNA FREUD CENTRE, 1991 November 1-2 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - DCYS, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - LEON ROSENBERG FAREWELL, 1991 November 16 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - NEW RESEARCH INTO AUTISM AND ITS PRACTICAL IMPLICATIONS, JERUSALEM, 1992 January 5 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - CSC LECTURE 122, 1992 January 13 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - MARTIN LUTHER KING DAY, 1992 January 21 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - BUSH CENTER IN CHILD DEVELOP. AND SOCIAL POLICY: NATIONAL COMMISSION ON CHILDREN: PERSONAL EXPERIENCES OF BEYOND RHETORIC, 1992 January 21 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - LEAGUE OF WOMEN VOTERS OF NEW HAVEN: MARGARET HITCHCOCK LECTURE SERIES: "OUR CHILDREN - OUR FUTURE", 1992 February 12 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - THE CHILD'S EMERGING UNDERSTANDING OF OTHER MINDS: LOVE AND AGGRESSION SRCD, NEW ORLEANS, LA, 1992 March 17 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - CLIFFORD BEERS LECTURE, SENATOR CHRISTOPHER DODD, 1992 April 6 (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - HANDOUTS: NEW DEVELOPMENTS IN SEVERE PSYCHIATRIC DISORDERS OF CHILDHOOD AMERICAN ACADEMY OF PEDIATRICS, 1992 April 12 (Box 5, Folder 256)
  - KANZER SEMINAR, 1986 February 13 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - ISRAEL PLAY AND TRAUMA MEETING, undated (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - CONTRIBUTIONS OF CLINICAL RESEARCH TO THE UNDERSTANDING OF THE MENTAL LIFE OF CHILDREN: PSYCHOBIOLOGY and CHILD PSYCHOANALYSIS: APA SYMPOSIUM, 1986 May (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - IACPAP, undated (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - NIMH-NATIONAL ADVISORY MENTAL HEALTH COUNCIL, undated (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - DIVISION SCIENCE SEMINAR WASHINGTON, DC, 1986 July 17 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - MENTAL DISORDERS and PSYCHOPHARMACOLOGY OF THE RETARDED: ANOTHER STEP IN SEEING THE WHOLE PERSON, 1986 November 17-18 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - CCRC, 1986 December 11 (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - PENNY PEOPLES, undated (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - DEAN'S COUNCIL MEETING, 1995 May 5 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - DEAN'S COUNCIL MEETING, 1991 January 21 (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - MEDICAL SCHOOL COUNCIL, YALE UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF MEDICINE, 1992 April 13 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - DEAN'S COUNCIL, 1991 May 16 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - MEDICAL SCHOOL COUNCIL, 1986 December 18 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - CAREER DEVELOPMENT OPPORTUNITY, undated (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - COMMITTEE ON COMMUNITY REL. PROPOSED ACQUIS. OF SELECTED TEMPLE MEDICAL ASSESTS, undated (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - COMMUNITY SERVICES SPONSORED BY THE SCHOOL OF MEDICINE and Y-NHH, undated (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - CURRICULUM COMMITTEE, 1990 March 15 (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - MEDICAL SCHOL STANDING COMMITTEES, undated (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - CSC CLINICAL SERVICES, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - CSC COMER SCHOOL DEVELOPMENTAL PROGRAM, undated (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - CSC CONFLICT OF INTEREST FORMS, undated (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - CSC COORDINATORS, 1984 February 17 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - CHILD STUDY CENTER COURSES, 1988-89 (Box 6, Folder 281)
  - CSC: DAVENPORT AVENUE, undated (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - CHILD STUDY CENTER: DAY CARE, 1999 August 9 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - CHILD STUDY CENTER: DEPARTMENT OF CHILDREN and FAMILIES (DCF), undated (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - DCF - MOBILE EMERGENCY PSYCHIATRIC SERVICES, undated (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - CHILD STUDY CENTER: ADMINISTRATION DCYS GRANT, 1991 April 3 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - DEPARTMENT OF CHILDREN AND FAMILIES ADVISORY BOARD MEETING THURSDAY, 1995 November 16 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - ADVISORY BOARD MEETING DEPARTMENT OF CHILDREN AND FAMILIES WEDNESDAY, 1995 June 21 (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - CSC/DEPARTMENT OF PSYCHIATRY, 1992-93 (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - YALE CHILD STUDY CENTER NAME CHANGE, 1995 February 7 (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - CSC: DEPARTMENT OF CHILD and ADOLESCENT PSYCHIATRY, THE YALE CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL, undated (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - YALE CHILD STUDY CENTER DEPARTMENTAL STATUS SCHOOL OF MEDICINE, 1988 July 11 (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - DEPARTMENT OF CHILD PSYCHIATRY YNHH, undated (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - ECA STUDY, 1991 February 15 (Box 6, Folder 294)
  - ECKMAN STUDY, undated (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - SCS FACULTY MEETING, 2001 June 28 (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - CSC FACULTY COMMITTEE, 1984 April 17 (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - DEDICATION, NEW WING, PRESENTATION ISRAEL, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 299)
    - MIND AND BODY TV SHOW, PRINCETON, NJ, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 300)
    - BAR ILAN UNIVERSITY HONORARY, DEGREE PRESENTATION, ISRAEL, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - Born digital files (Reel 7)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
- Child Study Center films, 1931-1947; Accession 2009-A-064 (Box 1–6)
  - "The Study of Infant Behavior" (parts 1-2) [22 min], 1931; computer file (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disc (DVD) (Box 1U)
  - "Infant Eyes and Hands" [9 min], 1941; computer file (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disc (DVD) (Box 2U)
  - "Comparison of Supine and Prone Postures of the Human Infant" [7 min], 1943; computer file (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disc (DVD) (Box 3U)
  - "Complete Congenital Anophthalmia - A Clinical Study of Early Mental Growth" [11 min], 1946; computer file (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disc (DVD) (Box 4U)
  - "Twins are Individuals" [11 min], 1946; computer file (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disc (DVD) (Box 5U)
  - "Handedness" [13 min], 1947; computer file (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disc (DVD) (Box 6U)
- Guidance Nursery yearly reports, 1940-1950; Accession 2010-A-085; 0.2; (1 envelope) (Box 1)
  The materials are open for research.
- School Development Program training manuals and other publications, Accession 2010-A-086; 3; (3 boxes)
  - Summary of School Development Program Documentation and Research, 1991 (Box 1)
  - School Development Program Research Monograph, 1994 May (Box 1)
  - School Development Program Quality Standards Process Documentation Inventory Manual, Circa 1995 (Box 1)
  - Principals' Academy Facilitators' Group, 1997 Summer (Box 1)
  - Leadership Development Program, 1998 January 26-30 (Box 1)
  - Creating Successful Urban Schools: The School Development Program and School Improvement, 1998 February (Box 1)
  - Leadership Development Program Skills Workshops, 1999 February 8-12 (Box 1)
  - National Academy for Leadership in Education: Summer Institute, 1999 July 21-23
  - Leadership Development Program 101 Training, 1999 October 4-8 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Development Program 101 Training Skills Workshop, Circa 2000 (Box 1)
  - 102 Leadership Training, Circa 2000 (Box 1)
  - Systemic Reform Initiative, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Development Program SDP Modules, 2000 January 24-28 (Box 1)
  - 102 Leadership Training, 2000 February 28-March 3 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Development Program 101 Training SDP Modules (Day 3 only), 2000 April 10-14 (Box 1)
  - 102 Leadership Development Program, 2000 May 15-19 (Box 1)
  - 102 Leadership Development Program Workshops, 2000 May 14-19 (Box 2)
  - District Context and Comer Schools: How School Districts Manage School Reform, 2000 June (Box 2)
  - National Academy for Leadership in Education: Summer Policy Institute, 2000 July 19-21 (Box 2)
  - 101 Leadership Training, 2000 October 30-November 3 (Box 2)
  - SDP Retreat: Workshop on Materials and Outcome Indicators that Make SDP Implementation Explicit, 2001 January (Box 2)
  - Principals' Academy, 2001 July 16-20 (Box 2)
  - National Academy for Leadership in Education: Summer Policy Institute, 2001 July 25-27 (Box 2)
  - 102 Leadership Development Program Skills workshops, Circa 2002 (Box 2)
  - Principals' Academy, 2002 July 8-12 (Box 2)
  - Implementation Coordinators' Manual, 2002 August (Box 2)
  - Comer Facilitators' Workshop I, 2002 September 2 (Box 2)
  - New Haven-Comer 2003: A Modified SDP Training, 2003 May 1-2 (Box 2)
  - Leadership Development Program: 102 Training, 2004 (Box 2)
  - School Development Program Academy for Developmentally Centered Education: Education = Development
    - Part I (days 1-2), 2004 March 15-19 (Box 3)
    - Part II (Days 3-5), 2004 March 15-19 (Box 3)
  - Grant Meeting, 2005 September 12 (Box 3)
  - School Development Program Academy for Developmentally Centered Education: Education = Development, 2006 January 30-February 2 (Box 3)
  - Understanding and Managing Student Behavior
    - Oklahoma City Public Schools, Circa 2007 (Box 3)
  - 101 Leadership Academy: Omni Hotel at Yale, New Haven, CT, 2007 April 23-26 (Box 4)
  - 102 Leadership Academy: Omni Hotel at Yale, New Haven, CT, 2007 April 23-26 (Box 4)
  - 101 Leadership Academy: Omni Hotel at Yale, New Haven, CT, 2007 November 12-15 (Box 4)
  - 102 Leadership Academy: Omni Hotel at Yale, New Haven, CT, 2007 November 12-15 (Box 4)
  - 101 Leadership Academy: Omni Hotel at Yale, New Haven, CT, 2008 April 28-May 1 (Box 4)
  - 102 Leadership Academy: Omni Hotel at Yale, New Haven, CT, 2008 April 28-May 1 (Box 4)
  - Modified 101 Leadership Academy: New Haven Public Schools, Amarante's Sea Cliff, 2008 May 22-23 (Box 4)
- Katherine Wolf research files, 1924-1980; Accession 2012-A-100; 3.5; (9 boxes)
  Restricted until January 1, 2050.
  Scope and Contents
  Records consist of child study files created primarily by Katherine Wolf. In addition to files on individual children, there are lantern slides, data files, and notes by other researchers.
  - Administrative files
    - C4 Brokelschen film analysis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Contour study, Circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Davitt and Reynolds -- stencil tracing and data, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Drawings and ditto masters for WK progress report, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Effects of visual stimulation upon sucking and limb movement in young infants -- raw data, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Evans -- repeated measures on a premature baby, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Excerpts from Rolf Ahrens' "A Contribution to the Development of the Recognition of Facial Expressions", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Excerpts of Catel, W., On the Brain Activity of the Newborn, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Experiment #303, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Experiment #303 and #304 and multiple observations of newborns, 1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Experiment #304, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fat group study -- DK, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Gutmann -- eye movements observations sheet 3, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Log Book #2 TA2, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Memorandum on evaluative observations, Circa 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Nipple/forehead figures and data, Circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Nipple/forehead research data, [No year] May 27 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Observation logs, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Observational drawings
      - Davitt B5
        - Day 1 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Day 2 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Day 3 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - Day 4 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
        - Day 5 observation 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Reynolds B6
        - Day 1 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Day 2 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Day 3 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Day 4 observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Day 5 Observation 1 and 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Raw data
      - Birth measurements, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - IBM punch card for K & K, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Research
      - Levison, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Milstein, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Samples -- drawings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Search sheets, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Simpson, L., infant profiles, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Subject data
      - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Vanguard prematures calibration, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Vanguard sheets and measurements, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - WK film notes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Interview forms
    - Pilot cohort, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cohort N7, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cohort N8, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
    - Cohort N68, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Cohort N468, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Cohort X8, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cohort X68, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Cohort X468, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Cohorts XA and XB, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Cohorts YA and YB, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Dropped subjects, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Data
    - Cohort data, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
      Index cards contain the records of individual infants.
    - Raw data sets
      - T121 F3, XY plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - TA
        - S#121, X plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - S#122, X and XY plots, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - S#123, X plot, 6-8 weeks, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - S#123 F3, XY plot, 6-8 weeks, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - S#130, X plot, newborn-8 weeks, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - S#134, X and XY plots, newborn-8 weeks, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - TA 1
        - S#104, X and XY plots, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - S#112, X and XY plots, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - S#113, XY plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - TB
        - 112 F3, XY plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - 113 F3, XY plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - 114 F3, XY plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
        - 115 F3, XY plot, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Lantern slides
    - K. Wolff, baby study data, slides 1-8, Undated (Box 9)
    - Unidentified data sets
      - #1, slides 1-2, Undated (Box 9)
      - #2, slides 1-3, Undated (Box 9)
    - Unidentified individual slides, 1-2, Undated (Box 9)
      These are possibly another data set.